Guide to the Chinese Students' Christian Association in North America Records
Yale University Divinity School Library
Chinese Students' Christian Association in North America Records
1909-1952
RG 13
Yale University Divinity School Library
1.5
(3 boxes)
The papers, though quite fragmentary, represent the most complete documentation available for the history of the Chinese Students' Christian Association, and provide a skeletal outline of its activities, policies and personnel. This collection is a noteworthy supplement to other record groups at the Divinity Library that document religious work among college and university students. The Chinese Students' Christian Association was organized in 1909 by four students from the universities of Yale, Columbia, Harvard and Michigan. The purpose of the Association was to foster Christian morals and friendships, and to unite Chinese Christian students living in American society. The Association provided practical services to Chinese students who were arriving from China, going to China or Europe, looking for homes or employment, needing to make purchases, or in need of other assistance.
Chinese Student Christian Association in North America
Conditions Governing Access
Open to qualified researchers.
Biographical / Historical
The Chinese Students' Christian Association was organized in 1909 under the leadership of Dr. C. T. Wang, Dr. P. W. Kuo, Dr. David Z. T. Yui, and Dr. W. C. Chen, then students at Yale, Columbia, Harvard, and Michigan respectively. The national Association had its central office in New York City. Its affairs were directed by a Central Executive Board composed of officers of its regional departments. Local units were formed where there were five or more students in harmony with the purpose of the Association. In 1949 the Association had 1,200 members in twenty-five local chapters. The Association was affiliated with the Committee on Friendly Relations Among Foreign Students of the International Committee of the Y.M.C.A.s of North America, the National Committee of the Y.M.C.A. in China, the Chinese Students' Christian Union of Great Britain and the Chinese Y.M.C.A. in France. The purpose of the Association was defined as follows in a 1931 publication:
To cultivate among the members and friends the Christ-like spirit and to apply His teachings in their daily lives and activities.
To build strong moral character and to foster the spirit of self-sacrifice and self-development by rendering service to members.
To unite those students in cooperative efforts for promoting programs and activities of the Association on various campuses.
To study and understand American life and society; and to interpret Chinese culture and civilization to America through writing, speaking, dramatics and friendly contacts.
The Association provided practical services to Chinese students who were arriving from China, going to China or Europe, looking for homes or employment, needing to make purchases, or in need of other assistance.
Scope and Contents
Though these records are quite fragmentary they probably represent the most complete documentation available for the history of the Chinese Students' Christian Association. Minutes and reports, correspondence of the Association's General Secretary, conference handbooks and publicity, periodical publications, and miscellaneous pamphlets provide a skeletal outline of the Association's activities, policies and personnel. Additional periodical publications of the Association are in the Library's cataloged collection. Additional records of the Chinese Students' Christian Association can be found in Record Group No. 46, Archives of the World Student Christian Federation.
This collection is a noteworthy supplement to other record groups at the Divinity Library that document religions work among college and university students.
Arrangement
I. Administrative, 1909-1950, n.d.
II. Correspondence, 1918-1950
III. Conferences and Activities, 1915-1950
IV. Publications, 1910-1950
V. Photographs, 1944, n.d.
Students, Foreign; Universities and colleges -- Religion; Chen, W. C.; Kuo, Ping Wen, 1880-1969; Wang, Quncong; Yui, David Z. T.; Chinese Student Christian Association in North America
- Administrative, 1909-1950,n.d.; Series I
  - Constitution, by-laws; Financial records, 1909-1922,n.d. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Student aid material, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Tax information and forms, 1949,1950 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Treasurer's reports, budgets, 1927-1951 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Minutes, agenda, 1914-1950 (Box 1, Folder 5-9)
  - Officers and staff Reports, 1916-1934,n.d. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Annual reports, 1911/12, 1912/13, 1931/32, 1949/50 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Monthly reports - typed, 1910 Nov,1944 Jan (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Monthly reports - printed (incomplete), 1911 Feb-1913 Apr (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Other official reports, 1911-1926 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Other official reports, 1943-1949,n.d. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Misc. reports and mss., 1910-1918,1945-1950,n.d. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Fragmentary reports and mes. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Committee on Friendly Relations Among Foreign Students Other administrative material, 1911-1952,n.d. (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Notes on C.S.C.A history and documents (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Miscellaneous, 1926/27, 1944,1948,n.d. (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Correspondence, 1918-1950; Series II
  - Bachelder, Ruth, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - C.S.C.A. in No. America form letters, 1931-1948. n.d. (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - C.S.C.A. Midwestern Office, 1946, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - C.S.C.A. Western Office, 1946-1949 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - C.S.C.A. of San Francisco, 1918 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Chu, H. T., 1946 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Committee on Friendly Relations, 1947, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Eng, Homer, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Federal Council of Churches of Christ in America, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Fisher, Welthy H., 1949 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Fletcher, Joseph, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Fong, S. H., 1949 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Foreign Missions Conference of North America, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Hein, Charles T., 1950, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Hoover, Lyman, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Hsia, David, 1946, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Johnson, Mrs. G. Neil, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - re. Judd Bill, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Kiang Wen-han, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Klinger, Robert B., 1948 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - re. Alfred Kohlberg letter to N.Y. Herald Tribune, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Kuo Hong-heu, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Kwoh, Edwin, 1947, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Lautenschlager, Stanton, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Lerrigo, Edith, 1949, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Li, C.W., 1948 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Lin, Paul T.K., 1946-1948 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Linton, Clarence, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Lions International, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Lobenstine, Edwin C., 1949 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Loucks, Harold H., 1949 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Mead, Mabel C., 1947 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - re. Meng, Francis F.T., 1950 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - National Committee of Y.M.C.A., Shanghai, 1946-1948 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - National Student Federation of China, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - National Student Relief Committee, Chungking, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Quan, Mary, 1946, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Stuart, J. Leighton, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Student Christian Movement of Canada, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Ting, K.H. and Siu May, 1948, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - United Board for Christian Colleges in China, 1949, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - United Chinese Christian Youth Movement in America, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - United States Department of State, 1945, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - United States Immigration and Naturalization Service, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Wang, T.H., 1948, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - West China Union University, Chengtu, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Wolferz, Louis and Katherine, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Y.W.C.A. of the U.S.A., 1949 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Yu Pei-wen, 1947, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 30)
- Conferences and Activities, 1915-1950; Series III
  - Conference material, 1915 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Conference material, 1942-1950,n.d. (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Conferences of related organizations: (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Chinese Students Alliance in the U.S.A., 1928, 1929 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Chinese Students' Association of the South, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - New Haven Students-in-Industry Project, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - TVA Travel Seminar, 1947, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 35)
- Publications, 1910-1950; Series IV
  - Directory of Chinese Students in America, 1910, 1915,1934/35-1939/40 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Pamphlets
    - Leaders for a New China, 1921 Oct (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Friendship, 1922 Aug (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Manchuria Before November 16, 1931 Nov (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - State Department Aid to Cultural Exchange, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - With China, 1944 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - An Open Letter to Fellow-Christians in North America, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - This is What They Say, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Periodicals
    - The Builder (1 issue), n.d. (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Chinese Christian Student (incomplete), 1931 May-1941 Dec (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - Chinese Student Opinion, 1948 Jun (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - C.S.C.A. Eastern Department Bulletin, 1948 Dec (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - C.S.C.A. Fellowship Notes (incomplete), 1922 Feb-1925 May (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - C.S.C.A. Midwest Bulletin, 1948 May (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - C.S.C.A. Yearbook, 1925-1928 (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - Christian China, 1922 May (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - Liu Mei Tsing Nien, 1917 Jan (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - Monthly Bulletin, 1914 Jan (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Publicity material
    - Brochures, etc., 1922-1931,1950 (Box 3, Folder 45)
- Photographs, 1944, n.d.; Series V
  - Portraits, unidentified or identified in Chinese, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Misc., mostly unidentified, 1944, n.d (Box 3, Folder 47)